A Finding Aid to the Carlen Galleries, Inc., Records, 1775-1997, bulk 1940-1986, in the Archives of American Art AAA.carlgall
Archives of American Art
Carlen Galleries, Inc., records
bulk 1940-1986
1775-1997
AAA.carlgall
Archives of American Art
9.25 Linear feet
The Carlen Galleries, Inc., records measure 10.4 linear feet (gift portions) and date from 1775 to 1997 (bulk 1940-1986). Correspondence, business records, subject files, a scrapbook, printed matter, and photographs document the operation and activities of Carlen Galleries, Inc., and its founder Robert Carlen.
Carlen Galleries.
Historical Note
Robert Carlen (1906-1990) worked as a secretary and attended evening classes at the Graphic Sketch Club in Philadelphia right after graduating from high school. He studied painting full-time at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts during the academic year 1928/29, and from 1929-1936 he continued to study painting in the evenings while employed at a brokerage firm.
Since he wanted to be associated with the art world and needed to earn a living, Carlen decided to establish an art gallery that would show the works of young artists. In 1937, he opened in Carlen Galleries in his home at 323 South 16th Street, Philadelphia; the galleries operated in the same location for the remainder of Carlen's life. In its earliest years, Carlen Galleries housed exhibitions of the Associated American Artists' Group and featured prints by Wanda Gag, Käthe Kollwitz, Louis Lozowick, Lynd Ward, and other print makers.
In 1941, paintings by Horace Pippin were exhibited at Carlen Galleries. Carlen soon befriended the artist and began providing him with art supplies. He remained Pippin's agent for many years following the artist's death in 1946, and was a sought-after authority on the artist's work and life.
By the mid-1940s, Carlen had discovered a painting by Edward Hicks in Bucks County, Pa. He began researching the then-obscure Quaker artist. Through contacting descendants of Hicks's patrons, Carlen was able to acquire many of Hicks's paintings and Carlen Galleries became known for handling important early American folk paintings and antiques. Among his clients were Edward W. and Bernice Chrysler Garbisch, Winterthur Museum, Winterthur, Del., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Museum, Williamsburg, Va., and the Shelburne Museum, Shelburne, Vt.
During the course of his long career, Robert Carlen served as an advisor to many Philadelphia collectors and developed an extensive knowledge of the genealogies and heirlooms of the city's prominent families. Because of his extensive experience and expertise, Carlen's opinion was widely valued and his services as an appraiser of art and antiques were in great demand.
Scope and Content Note
The Carlen Galleries, Inc., records measure 10.4 linear feet (gift portions, Parts 1 and 3) and date from 1775-1998 (bulk 1940-1986). Correspondence, business records, subject files, a scrapbook, printed matter, and photographs document the operation and activities of Carlen Galleries, Inc., and its founder Robert Carlen.
Part 1: Received in 1986 as a gift from Robert Carlen, these records document the activities of Carlen Galleries and its founder, 1937-1986. Correspondence mainly concerns the sale and purchase of works of art. Also included are artist files containing correspondence, receipts, and printed matter regarding Albert Davies, Edward Hicks, Käthe Kollwitz, Horace Pippin, and Maurice Prendergast. Subject files concern African American artists, Raphael Peale, Raymond Feuillate, and the French Moderns. Business records consist of loan forms, documentation of exhibitions at Carlen Galleries, inventories, a scrapbook and clippings concerning the gallery, conservation reports, appraisals (not microfilmed), and financial records.
Part 2: Additional records documenting the activities of Carlen Galleries and its founder, 1937-1986, were loaned by Robert Carlen for microfilming in 1988. Included are letters about Horace Pippin and rare letters from the artist. Other correspondence concerns Carlen's search for paintings by Edward Hicks, and there is also a small selection of letters regarding more routine gallery business. Among the business records are and account book and receipts. Printed matter consists of exhibition catalogs, announcements, and clippings; a scrapbook contains printed matter about Horace Pippin. Photographs are of Allan Freelon and works of art.
Part 3: Received in 2002 as a gift from Robert Carlen's daughter Nancy Carlen, this portion of the Carlen Galleries, Inc., Records consists of two letters, business records, photographs, and selections from the galleries' library. Letters are from Joan Baez, circa 1960 and Charles M. Mount, 1968. Previously sealed letters from Charles M. Mount, undated, and 1962-1975, relating to John Singer Sargent have been integrated into this portion.
Part 4: Additional records borrowed for microfilming from Nancy Carlen in 2002 include documents dated 1775-1997 (bulk 1940s-1990). Correspondence concerns gallery business, but a small amount of personal correspondence is also included. Business records consist of appraisal reports, receipts for sales and purchases, and the contract and program for the 1964 University [of Pennsylvania] Hospital Antiques Show in which Carlen Galleries exhibited. Subject files document Edward Hicks, Anatol Jal, the Captain James Lawrence Goblet, Horace Pippin, and Antoine Roux. Five notebooks, containing material similar to that in the subject files, are about Horace Pippin (vols. 1-3), Edward Hicks (vol. 4), and chronicle the career of Robert Carlen (vol. 5).
Printed matter consists of clippings and other items concerning art and antiques, Robert Carlen and Carlen Galleries, Inc., and the Diplomatic Reception Rooms of the State Department where two Hicks paintings owned by Carlen were on extended loan. Among the miscellaneous records are biographical documents, personal financial records, business and research notes (including original documents and photocopies of archival materials), and four prints. Photographs are mostly of antiques and art work; also included are a few pictures of people, places, and miscellaneous subjects.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four parts, representing gift and loan accessions received and microfilmed at various times. The two loans for microfilming (Parts 2 and 4) overlap and partially duplicate one another-particularly records relating to Horace Pippin and Edward Hicks-but are far from identical. Some of the Pippin and Hicks material was significantly rearranged in the interim between the first loan (1988) and the second (2002).
Part 1: Gift (1986), 1906-1986 (Boxes 1-7; 7.0 linear feet; Reels 4166-4175)
Part 2: Loan (1988), 1937-1986 (Reel 4175)
Part 3: Gift (2002), 1835-1992 (Boxes 8-12; 3.4 linear feet; Reel 5745)
Part 4: Loan (2002), 1775-1997 (Reels 5746-5748)
Provenance
The collection was acquired in various accessions of gifts and loans. Part 1: gift of Robert Carlen, 1986; Part 2: loaned by Robert Carlen for microfilming, 1988; Part 3: gift of Nancy Carlen, 2002 (previously sealed letters and appraisals received with Part 1 are housed with Part 3 and integrated for microfilming); Part 4: loaned by Nancy Carlen for microfilming, 2002.
Restrictions on Access
Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available on microfilm reels 4166-4175, 5745, and 5746-5748. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Davies, Albert Webster, 1889-1967; Feuillate, Raymond, 1901-1971; Gainsborough, Lee; Hicks, Edward, 1780-1849; Kollwitz, Käthe, 1867-1945; Peale family; Pippin, Horace, 1888-1946; Prendergast, Maurice Brazil, 1858-1924; African American artists; Art appraisers; Art dealers; Art galleries, Commercial--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia; Art--Collectors and collecting; Art--Exhibitions; Decorative arts--United States; Folk art--United States; Painters; Photographs; Scrapbooks
- Gift (1986), 1906-1986; Series 1; 7 Linear feet Boxes 1-7; Reels 4166-4175
  Arrangement note
  Part 1 is arranged into 18 series:
  1.1: Finding Guide
  1.2: Correspondence, 1937-1986
  1.3: Artist Files: Edward Hicks, 1944-1975
  1.4: Artist Files: Albert Davies, 1960-1976
  1.5: Artist Files: Horace Pippin, 1940-1975
  1.6: Subject Files: Information on Black Artists, 1940-1945
  1.7: Subject Files: Correspondence Not to or From Carlen, 1933-1977
  1.8: Business Records: Loan Forms, 1959-1970
  1.9: Business Records: Carlen Gallery Exhibitions, 1938-1970
  1.10: Business Records: Miscellaneous Art Work Information, 1906-1977
  1.11: Business Records: Photographs, 1952
  1.12: Business Records: Miscellaneous Inventories, 1966-1976
  1.13: Business Records: Advertising, 1946-1959
  1.14: Business Records: Guest Book, 1938
  1.15: Business Records: Scrapbook, 1937-1938
  1.16: Business Records: Clippings (photocopies), 1950-1977
  1.17: Business Records: Conservation Reports, 1950-1979
  1.18: Business Records: Financial Records, 1938-1980
  - Finding Guide, undated; 1.1
    Scope and Contents note
    A target for a finding guide appears on the microfilm and the same information is on the microfilm box label, but there is no evidence that the Finding Guide was ever produced.
  - Correspondence, 1937-1986; 1.2
    Correspondence, arranged chronologically, consists mainly of letters from artists, dealers, curators, and collectors concerning the sale and purchase of works of art. Additional correspondence files concern sales of paintings by Maurice Prendergast, 1959-1975, and Käthe Kollwitz, 1938-1980.
    - Correspondence, 1937-1953; (14 folders) (Box 1, Reel 4166)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955; (9 folders) (Box 1, Reel 4167)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-Nov., 1956; (4 folders) (Box 2, Reel 4167)
    - Correspondence, Nov., 1956-April, 1959; (13 folders) (Box 2, Reel 4168)
    - Correspondence, April-Dec., 1959; (4 folders) (Box 2, Reel 4169)
    - Correspondence, 1960-Dec., 1961; (8 folders) (Box 3, Reel 4169)
    - Correspondence, Dec., 1961-1964; (9 folders) (Box 3, Reel 4170)
    - Correspondence, 1965-Aug., 1966; (8 folders) (Box 4, Reel 4170)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1971; (15 folders) (Box 4, Reel 4171)
    - Correspondence, 1972; (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4171)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1986, undated; (14 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4172)
    - Maurice Prendergast (letters and sales receipts), 1959-1975, undated; (14 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4172)
    - Käthe Kollwitz (letters, sales receipts, and printed matter), 1938-1980, undated (Box 5, Reel 4172)
  - Artist Files: Edward Hicks, 1944-1975; 1.3
    - Letters Regarding Edward Hicks Paintings, fragments, 1943-1948, undated (Box 5, Reel 4172)
    - Letters Regarding Edward Hicks Paintings, 1948-1976 (Box 5, Reel 4173)
    - Receipts for Purchases of Edward Hicks Paintings, 1945-1974, undated (Box 5, Reel 4173)
    - Printed Matter, 1944-1975, undated (Box 5, Reel 4173)
  - Artist Files: Albert Davies, 1960-1976; 1.4
    - Letters from Albert Davies, 1962-1964, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Letters Regarding Purchase/Sale of Albert Davies Works, 1960-1976, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Commission Account and Consignment Receipts, Kennedy Galleries, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Sales Receipts, Exhibition Catalog, 1960-1965, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
  - Artist Files: Horace Pippin, 1940-1970; 1.5
    - Letters from Horace Pippin, 1941-1946, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Letters Relating to Horace Pippin, 1940-1979, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Financial Material (receipts and sales reports), 1940-1970, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Miscellaneous Lists and Inventories, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, Checklists, Photographs, 1937-1966, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Clippings (photocopies), 1941-1944, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
  - Subject Files: Information on Black Artists, 1940-1945; 1.6
    - Speech by Unidentified Author on Negro Artists, circa 1945 (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Letters to Madelin Blitzstein Relating to Black Artists, 1945 (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Miscellaneous Information on Black Artists, 1940, 1945, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
  - Subject Files: Correspondence, Not Carlen, 1933-1977; 1.7
    - Letters Written and Received by Various Correspondents, 1933-1977 (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Letters to Mrs. Almon Kidder Concerning Raphaelle Peale, 1942-1967 (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Raymond Feuillatte (includes exhibition catalog), 1946 (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - French Moderns (photocopies of correspondence, receipts, printed matter), 1963-1966 (Box 6, Reel 4173)
  - Business Records: Loan Forms, 1959-1975; 1.8
    These files include related correspondence and printed matter.
    - Loans from Carlen Gallery, 1959-1974, undated (Box 6, Reel 4173)
    - Loans from Carlen Gallery, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Carlen Galleries Exhibitions, 1938-1970; 1.9
    - Exhibition Price Lists, 1938-1970, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
    - Photographs, Invoices, Invitation copy, 1949-1950, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
    - Printed Matter, 1948-1957, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Miscellaneous Art Work Information, 1906-1977; 1.10
    These two files include a statement of authenticity from the Lotos Club, 1906; two pamphlets written and published by Albert C. Barnes, undated; draft of talk about Carlen's experiences as an art appraiser, undated; includes descriptions of paintings, biographical notes on artists, and provenance of Alexander Calder work owned by Cleve Gray, 1979.
    - Miscellaneous, 1906-1971, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
    - Miscellaneous Art Work Information, 1977-1979, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Photographs, 1952; 1.11
    This file includes 7 views of display windows, Blum Store, Philadelphia, featuring women's suits and weathervanes and a passport portrait of Robert Carlen.
    - Weathervane Photographs, Robert Carlen, 1952, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Miscellaneous Inventories, 1966-1976; 1.12
    Some of these inventories include value/price and numbers that may indicate stock number or location.
    - Miscellaneous Carlen Galleries Inventories, 1966-1976 (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Advertising, 1946-1959; 1.13
    - Advertising, 1946-1959, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Guest Book, 1938; 1.14
    One volume, with cover lacking, noting artist and exhibition dates; also includes "A. A. List" of names in alphabetical order [mailing list?]; and an undated price list for antiques.
    - Guest Book, 1938 (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Scrapbook, 1937-1938; 1.15
    One volume spiral notebook titled Carlen Galleries containing clippings, mainly exhibition notices and reviews, feature stories on artists shown by Carlen Galleries; also includes handwritten list of "Local Negro Art".
    - Scrapbook, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Clippings, 1950-1977; 1.16
    Clippings about folk art, art sales, artists, and Carlen Galleries exhibitions.
    - Clippings, 1950-1977, undated (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Conservation Reports, 1950-1979; 1.17
    Conservation reports and invoices with descriptions of conservation work performed on items belonging to Carlen Galleries, Inc.
    - Conservation Reports, 1950-1979; (3 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4174)
  - Business Records: Financial Records, 1938-1980; 1.18
    - Account with Lee Gainsborough, 1945 (Box 6, Reel 4174)
    - Audit Records, 1970 (Box 6, Reel 4174)
- Loan (1988), 1937-1986; Series 2; (Reel 4175)
  Part 2 is arranged into five subseries:
  2.1: Letters, 1941-1986
  2.2: Business Records, 1937-1946
  2.3: Printed Matter, 1937-1947
  2.4: Scrapbook, 1937-1947
  2.5: Photographs, 1944
  - Letters, 1941-1986; 2.1
    Some of the Horace Pippin and Edward Hicks material microfilmed with part 2 is partially duplicated in Part 4, but was significantly rearranged in the interim.
    - Relating to Horace Pippin, 1942-1947, undated (Box NA, Reel 4175)
    - From Horace Pippin, 1941-1945, undated (Box NA, Reel 4175)
    - Relating to Edward Hicks, 1946-1947, undated (Box NA, Reel 4175)
    - General, 1946-1986, undated (Box NA, Reel 4175)
  - Business Records, 1937-1946; 2.2
    - Account Book, 1937-1938 (Box NA, Reel 4175)
    - Receipts, 1940-1947, undated (Box NA, Reel 4175)
  - Printed Matter, 1937-1947; 2.3
    Includes exhibition announcements, catalogs, and clippings.
    - Printed Matter, 1937-1947 (Box NA, Reel 4175)
  - Scrapbook, 1937-1947; 2.4
    - Horace Pippin Scrapbook, 1937-1947 (Box NA, Reel 4175)
  - Photographs, 1944; 2.5
    Includes photographs of undated works of art, and a 1944 portrait of Allan Freelon.
    - Photographs, 1944, undated (Box NA, Reel 4175)
- Gift (2002), 1835-1992; Series 3; 3.4 Linear feet Boxes 8-12; Reel 5745
  This series includes previously sealed letters and appraisals.
  Part 3 is arranged into four subseries:
  3.1: Letters, 1962-circa 1980
  3.2: Business Records, 1904-1979
  3.3: Photographs, circa 1940, circa 1950
  3.4: Selections from Library of Carlen Galleries, Inc., 1835-1992(unfilmed)
  - Letters, 1962- circa 1980; 3.1
    This subseries includes previously sealed letters from Charles M. Mount received with Part 1, but not available for research until 2002.
    - Mount, Charles M. (previously sealed), 1962-1964 (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
    - Mount, Charles M., 1968 (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
    - Mount, Charles M. (previously sealed), 1968-1975, undated (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
    - Baez, Joan, circa 1980 (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
  - Business Records, 1979; 3.2
    This subseries ncludes previously sealed appraisals received with Part 1.
    - Sales Receipt (for The Crucifixion by Pippin, 1943, sold to Menil Foundation), 1979 (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
    - List of Paintings for Appraisal, undated (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
    - Appraisals (previously sealed) (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Acton - Bergman, 1964-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Bernstein, Benjamin, 1957-1971 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Bernstein, Edward, 1959-1970 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Bernstein, Stanley, 1970-1978 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Bethlehem Steel - Borowsky, 1949-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Bortin, David, 1962-1972 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Bortin, George, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Bostwick - Brinley, 1968-1976 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Briskin, Edward B., 1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Brooke - Claxton, 1957-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Cole - Davis, 1961-1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Dechert, Price & Rhoads, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Decker - Drinker, 1962-1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Duane, Morris, 1904-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Dubin - Fineberg, 1962-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - First City Troop - Free Library of Philadelphia, 1960-1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Fried, Herbert, 1964-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Friedland - Gardner, 1959-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Gardner, Robert T., 1967-1968 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Giles - Golden, 1962-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Goldman, William, 1957-1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Goldsmith - Grant, 1959-1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Greenberg, Jennye, 1963-1970 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Greenfield, Albert M., 1967 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Greenhouse - Griscom, 1960-1973 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Grossman, David J., 1968-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Gutman, Jacob C., 1960-1967 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Haas, John C., 1966-1968 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Hahn, Maruice and Roslyn, 1959-1966 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Hallowell - Hellenbranth, 1964-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Henderson, J. Welles, 1961-1978 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Hendrix - Jaffe, 1962-1978 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Jaffee, Wilton, 1961-1976 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - James - Kvaines, 1961-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Laessle - Levin, G., 1957-1976 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Levin, Mrs. Lionel, 1973 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Levy - Mann, 1959-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Markowitz - Mitchell, 1953-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Moore, Matthew T., 1965-1973 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Morris - Pesin, 1958-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Philadelphia Bar Association, 1966, undated (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Philadelphia Saving Fund Society - Phillips, 1961-1973 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Pleet, Mrs. Gilbert, 1959-1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Potamkin, Mr. and Mrs. Meyer P., 1956-1973 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Potamkin, S. - Potamkin, V., 1964-1969 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Pratt, Elmer, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Presby - Robertson, 1963-1976 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Robinson, Ira Earl, 1958-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Rock - Rosenberg, 1967-1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Rosenfeld, Mrs. A. J., 1975 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Rosich - Schroeder, 1957-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Carl Schurz Association, Inc., 1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Scott - Shapiro, M., 1968-1977 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Shapiro, Sam, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Sharpe - Sheetz, 1969-1974 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Shein, Joseph D., 1970-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Shenkin - Shinners, 1957-1972 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Silverman, Robert L. and Marilyn, 1959-1966 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Silverman, Samuel S. and Norma B., 1959-1971 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Simon - Smith, 1964-1978 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Snellenberg, Stanley S., 1957-1974 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Snitzer, Edward, 1965-1979 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Soffian - Sulkowski, 1958-1976 (Box 10, Reel 5745)
      - Sullivan, Robert J., 1969-1978 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Sundheim - Wheelock, 1957-1976 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Wheelwright, Ellen duPont, 1969 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Wherry, Frank G., 1975 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Williams - Winters, 1968-1977 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Wistar Institute, 1970-1977 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Wolf - York, 1961-1977 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Zeidman, Elizabeth G., 1967-1974 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Zinman - Zobian, 1971-1974 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
      - Zvegintzov, Mr. and Mrs. Alexander A., 1966 (Box 11 (pam), Reel 5745)
  - Photographs, circa 1940, circa 1950; 3.3
    - Robert Carlen (one by Adiran Siegel, photographer), circa 1950, undated (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
    - Robert Carlen with Mrs. Jennie Ora Pippin and Horace Pippin (Arnold Newman, photographer), circa 1940 (Box 8 (pam), Reel 5745)
  - Selections from Library of Carlen Galleries, Inc., 1835-1992; 3.4
    The filing order and subject designations of these catalogs, pamphlets, and periodicals, were supplied by the donor. A small number of folders include notes, photographs, and photocopies of archival material.
    - African, 1940-1968 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Almanac, 1835 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - American Colonial, 1954 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - American Journal of Numismatics and Bulletin of American Numismatic and Archaeological Societies, Boston, July 1885 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - American Painting, City Art Museum of St. Louis ( American Painting, 39th Annual Exhibition Vol. XXXI, No. 1 of the Bulletin), 1946 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - American West ( The West in Bronze, Kennedy Galleries, Inc., New York), 1968 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Americana, 1949 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Americana, 1978 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Associated American Artists, New York ( Patron's Supplement No. 35, 36, 1946 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art ( Two Hundred and Fifty Years of Painting in Maryland, 1945 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
    - Barlach, Ernst, 1956, 1984 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)